So there is some good news for the
architecture fraternity. Actually, COA has
taken a very good step for the
architecture fraternity.
What is the actual issue for the architecture fraternity? Like, if we, being an
architect, go to buy insurance
anywhere, then we do not face
any problem, irrespective of the profession,
like a doctor or a CA, what
discount do they get? It is different for them, they
buy insurance, but there is
nothing for architects. Whether you are an
architect or not, you had to buy insurance like a
normal person
and this was going on for a long time. I
mean, there was a discussion going on in the architecture fraternity for a long time. For the
last one or two years, I have been hearing
that there was a lot of discussion on this that
architects are facing a lot of issues like
in making insurance claims or why it costs them
so much more than the general
people. But since we are licensed
architects, what are the benefits for us? We have
just worked on that
and CO has announced it. I received that
email yesterday.  This is from the COA and all the
registered architects like us have been
sent an email and they have
announced three new insurances
which are going to be only
for architects. Okay, so let me
tell you about the three insurances here. The first one is personal
accident insurance, so if you
are a registered architect then personal
insurance is going to be for you people, the
second one is going to be health insurance and the
third one is going to be professional insured insurance.
Basically, what happens is that if
you are travelling, keep visiting the site, then as an
architect you have to visit the site, if
something goes wrong or there is a loss of life, then an
insurance is going to be made for them. The second one is when we have to fight legal issues,
suppose someone files a case against us
or a client files a case
or an employee files a case or the employee faces any
issue and someone files a case for deformation on that, then whatever
legal
charges are incurred for that, whatever money is incurred, all of that is included
in your insurance.  It is going to be covered
and the third one is health
insurance and here you will get to
see very good benefits, I mean
why it was said for architects
because you will get very cheap insurance,
I myself must have
told you guys some time back that when I
took insurance for my parents, it was quite costly,
I was looking for it for myself, so that was also quite
costly, okay, but right now what I am
seeing here is the rates, which I have reached by clicking on their website,
they have collaborated with IIC
Lombard General Insurance
and with KM Dastur, so the
collaboration has been done with both of them
and policies have been launched especially for architects,
now if I
tell you its rates, then suppose if
you are taking health insurance and the
good thing about health insurance is that you
can take it for yourself and for your parents, you can also
take it for your children, that is,
you can take
insurance for whoever is dependent on you, that is  It will cover your family as well, so
suppose you are
taking insurance up to 10 lakhs for yourself,
if you want to get covered
in health insurance, then its premium will be
₹ 318, which if you
convert it for a month, it will come to ₹ 609,
meaning you can pay it monthly if you want, then it will
cost ₹ 609, similarly if you
take insurance for 5 lakhs, only health insurance for
5 lakhs, then this will cost you
₹ 5000000, if you look at it yearly, it will be ₹ 300
something and if you take the one for legal issues,
which is going to be our
insurance, which is going to be the insurance, which is
made for architects,
whatever happens with deformation to fight legal issues,
our charges are there, so for them,
if you take insurance up to 10 lakhs,
get insurance cover of 10 lakhs, then there
you will have to pay only the premium
₹2000000 has to be paid annually, so
that is something which is a very lucrative
option that has emerged for us here
and trust me, this is something which you
can say that whatever the COA
says, the steps they have taken are
directly beneficial for us,
so this is something which is very good
and according to me, it is very good, rest I do
n't know whatever is going to happen on the ground, that is, what will be
implemented or
not, but yes, good steps have been
taken and you
can check it out by going to their website, I have given the link
in the description below, you
can also go and check it out from there and please share this video with your friends
and other
architects and your professionals
because this is something which they should definitely have to buy at least
because there should be no joke about health insurance
and there should be no joke about your legal
issues.  No, it looks like 00 years old,
1200 years old, okay, so there is no money at all, there is almost no
money, so
trust me, go for it and I am
giving the link in the description below, you can check it out.